Today's show of sympathy is about to begin.
今天的慰问活动即将开始。
Soldiers of the Empire
帝国士兵
for the great cause of East Asia's co-prosperity,
为了东亚共同繁荣的伟大事业，
for your participation in the Holy War,
为了你参与圣战，
on behalf of all the officers and men,
我代表全体官兵，
on behalf of all the officers and soldiers.
我代表全体官兵。
Applause.
掌声。
For the empire.
为了帝国。
What about
关于什么
I still can't make it.
我还是来不及
When are you going to give me the key?
你什么时候给我钥匙？
To be honest,
说实话，
when you were not here,
当你不在的时候
I've looked through the entire house.
我已经把整个房子都看遍了。
I really want to know
我真的很想知道
where you hid the key now.
你现在把钥匙藏在哪里。
You haven't opened my book, have you?
你还没打开我的书吧？
You are a traitor!
你是叛徒！
I am not.
我不是。
It's from Japan.
它来自日本。
And the one in your hand,
还有你手里的那个，
there are seven keys in total.
总共有七把钥匙。
The Wave dance begins.
波浪舞开始。
Of the First Ranking.
排名第一的。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
What do I mean?
我是什么意思？
Hurry up.
赶快。
A little lower.
低一点。
Move down a bit.
向下移动一点。
To the right.
向右。
Hurry up!
赶快！
Take it back!
把它收回！
What's up
这是怎么回事
put it back.
把它放回去。
Where's the key?
钥匙在哪里？
Shine the light on it.
用灯光照射它。
A little forward.
向前一点。
Watch out!
小心！
To the left.
向左转。
Give it to me.
把它给我。
Come on.
快点。
This is the last chance.
这是最后的机会了。
It's coming!
它来了！
To the right.
向右。
This is the second key.
这是第二把钥匙。
Commander Shanxia is anxious to see me.
山霞司令急着要见我。
What is it?
它是什么？
According to Jiang Zhaoguo's information,
According to Jiang Zhaoguo's information,
we contacted
我们联系了
the spy in Communist Zone.
共产主义区的间谍。
Verified that an alias Li Yupu
经核实，别名为李玉璞
who was involved in the design and printing of the currency.
谁参与了货币的设计和印刷。
He absconded a while ago.
他不久前潜逃了。
Look at this.
看这个。
This photo is of
这张照片是
this is an surveillance video of
这是一段监控视频
who lurked in Yan'an Communist Zone
谁潜伏在延安共产主义区
after his identity was exposed,
身份曝光后，
he stole the copper engraving in the border area
他偷走了边境地区的铜版画
I think I've seen this person recently.
我想我最近见过这个人。
He looks familiar.
他看起来很熟悉。
You met him?
你见过他吗？
I remember that
我记得那个
we have caught this person.
我们已经抓住这个人了。
He is currently detained
目前他已被拘留
of Military Police Headquarters.
宪兵司令部。
Really?
真的吗？
To make it through.
为了渡过难关。
Now we have to fight.
现在我们必须战斗。
Rush there!
冲过去！
Don't take the risk!
不要冒险！
Let me think.
让我想想。
What for? We have no time.
做什么的？我们没有时间。
If you don't leave, I will.
如果你不离开，我就会离开。
It's almost over. Give me the key.
快结束了。把钥匙给我。
Give me the key.
把钥匙给我。
Wang Dapu.
Wang Dapu.
Wang Dapu?
Wang Dapu?
How did you know about Dayan?
您是怎么知道达扬的？
It's me.
这就是我。
I was...
我曾是...
I heard it from...
我从...听说的
From Manager Luo.
罗经理发来的。
How did you know
你怎么知道
wang Dapu is Dayan's?
王大璞是大研的？
I saw him making the key
我看见他制作钥匙
In the cell.
在牢房里。
This is extremely exquisite.
这是非常精致的。
I heard that
我听说
dayan was a bronze carver.
大雁是一位青铜雕刻师。
So I guessed
所以我猜
wang Dapu could be Dayan.
wang Dapu could be Dayan.
In that case,
在这种情况下，
why didn't you report it to us?
你为什么不向我们报告？
Officer Uchida.
内田警官。
If I report to you,
如果我向你汇报的话
he will be arrested and interrogated for several times.
他将被多次逮捕和审讯。
But he will keep his mouth shut.
但他会闭嘴。
However,
然而，
I was thinking...
我刚在想...
If I escape with him,
如果我和他一起逃走的话
I might be able to find the copper plate.
我也许能找到那块铜板。
You think I'll believe you?
你觉得我会相信你吗？
The five of hearts
红心五人
are a team, aren't they?
是一个团队，不是吗？
Officer Uchida.
内田警官。
I'm really not the Five of Hearts.
我真的不是红心五人。
If I can find the copper plate this time,
如果这次我能找到铜板的话
to prove my innocence.
以证明我的清白。
Uchida Officer, please trust me.
内田警官，请相信我。
But Wang Dapu doesn't trust you.
但王大璞不信任你。
He ran away.
他逃跑了。
To trap you here.
要把你困在这里。
Officer Uchida.
内田警官。
Think about it.
想一想。
If Wang Dapu is really
如果王大璞真的是
with Wang Dapu,
和王大璞一起，
how could he leave me behind?
他怎么能丢下我呢？
Wang Dapu is now gone,
王大璞现在已经不在了，
you can't get close to him anymore.
你不能再靠近他了。
I can find him.
我能找到他。
Is that so?
是这样吗？
On Mai Yang Road,
位于麦阳路，
an abandoned oil factory on Mai Yang Road
麦阳路一座废弃的油厂
why?
为什么？
After he was locked up,
他被关起来后，
the only time he left the detention center
他唯一一次离开看守所
was to work at the oil factory
是在油厂工作
he knows the environment
他了解环境
and he's very familiar with the environment.
而且他对环境也很熟悉。
The Gendarmes are looking for him
宪兵正在寻找他
I think
我认为
he must be hiding there.
他肯定藏在那里。
Officer in the third.
官居第三。
I will find the copper plate.
我会找到铜板。
Please trust me.
请相信我。
Alright.
好吧。
I'll give you this opportunity.
我会给你这个机会。
Thank you, Officer Ueda.
谢谢你，上田警官。
Chen Jiaping is dead.
陈家平死了。
That's impossible.
这不可能。
Officer Uchida.
内田警官。
Is that a joke?
这是一个笑话吗？
Why would I?
我为什么要？
How did he die?
他怎么死的？
Who killed him?
谁杀了他？
I killed him myself.
我亲手杀了他。
Why did you kill him?
你为什么杀他？
He escaped from prison with a criminal.
他与一名罪犯一起越狱。
And were caught on the spot.
并被当场抓获。
Prison break?
越狱？
Why is that?
这是为什么？
Officer Uchida.
内田警官。
We found her.
我们找到了她。
Five of hearts is Zhao An.
红心五是赵安。
Chen Jia Ping is innocent,
陈家平是无辜的，
are you blaming me
你在怪我吗
for killing innocent people?
为了杀害无辜的人？
I didn't mean that.
我不是那个意思。
That boy is to blame.
那个男孩应该受到责备。
He was unlucky.
他很不幸。
You are anxious to see Director Jiang?
你急着要见江主任吗？
What exactly is it?
到底是什么？
Something important?
有什么重要的事情吗？
Where's Director Jiang?
姜主任呢？
He is having a meeting inside.
他正在里面开会。
Please.
请。
We haven't contacted Dayan for a long time.
我们已经很久没有联系达扬了。
If we contact him rashly,
如果我们贸然联系他，
when we contact him, right?
当我们联系他的时候，对吗？
Do you think that
你认为
to the wild goose?
到大雁那里去？
We might run into those who come from Yan'an.
我们可能会遇到那些从延安来的人。
Or caught by the Japanese.
或者被日本人抓住。
It's all possible.
这一切都有可能。
I heard you wanted to see me.
我听说你想见我。
Left Shuangtao, what are you doing?
离开双桃，你在做什么？
Drop the gun!
放下枪！
Put it down!
放下它！
Why did you do this?
你为什么要这么做？
Left Twin Peach.
左双桃。
Do you know what you're doing?
你知道你在做什么吗？
Put the gun down!
把枪放下！
Why you want to frame Chen Jia Ping?
为什么要陷害陈家平？
I framed Chen Jia Ping?
我陷害陈家平？
Didn't you know it was to protect you?
你不知道这是为了保护你吗？
However,
然而，
chen Jia Ping died.
chen Jia Ping died.
Chen Family Ping died?
陈家萍死了？
He was killed by you.
他被你杀了。
Chen Jiaping is dead?
陈家平死了？
That a traitor might die,
叛徒可能会死，
or a hidden CCP is dead.
或者隐藏的中共已经死了。
Do you have to be that sad?
有必要这么伤心吗？
Director Jiang,
Director Jiang,
don't you have anyone you love?
你没有爱的人吗？
Have you ever loved anyone?
你曾经爱过一个人吗？
Don't forget that
别忘了
you are doing a mission
你正在执行任务
chen Jia Ping is a tool you pretended to use.
陈家平是你假装使用的工具。
When did you start separating private interests from private interests?
您什么时候开始将私人利益与私人利益分开？
Have you ever suspected
你有没有怀疑过
about Chen Jia Ping's identity?
关于陈家平的身份？
Or did you already suspect that?
或者你已经怀疑了？
But you kept it a secret from me.
但你却对我隐瞒了。
You can even say that
你甚至可以这样说
your faith has started to deteriorate.
你的信仰已经开始恶化。
My belief has not changed.
我的信念没有改变。
You are changing.
你正在改变。
It's you all.
都是你们啊
Everything you're doing right now
你现在所做的一切
Is still anti-Japanese and saving the country?
还是抗日救国？
Are you still doing all that?
你还在做这一切吗？
Your so-called counterfeiting plan
你所谓的造假计划
that you were trying to forge the border?
你试图建立边界？
It is our Anti-Japanese Alliance.
这是我们的抗日同盟。
And millions of Chinese people.
还有数百万中国人民。
Why are you doing this?
你为什么做这个？
Director Jiang,
Director Jiang,
I know my subordinates well.
我很了解我的下属。
Zuo Shuangtao was acting on impulse.
左双涛是一时冲动。
Let her go outside to calm down.
让她到外面去冷静一下。
Let her go out to calm down.
让她出去冷静一下。
Lock her up first.
先把她锁起来。
Alright.
好吧。
Come on.
快点。
It's fine if you always complain to me.
如果你总是向我抱怨也没关系。
How can you really
你怎么能真的
look at yourself.
看看你自己。
Answer me sincerely.
真诚地回答我。
Was I really wrong?
我真的错了吗？
We are all executors of orders.
我们都是命令的执行者。
Political issues are complicated.
政治问题很复杂。
They have their own reasons
他们有自己的理由
they have their own reasons.
他们有自己的理由。
We don't need to ask too much.
我们不需要问太多。
But I don't think
但我不认为
you are not as determined as before
你不像以前那么坚定
how did Chen Jia Ping die?
陈家平怎么死的？
He and another wanted criminal
他和另一名通缉犯
were caught...
被抓了……
When he escaped from the prison.
当他逃出监狱时。
It was Neitian.
是内天。
Uchida killed him with her own hands.
内田亲手杀了他。
Did you see the corpse?
你看到尸体了吗？
I think
我认为
he'll give you a surprise.
他会给你一个惊喜。
Do you think
你认为
chen Jiaping will still be alive?
陈家平还会活着吗？
You really love him.
你真的很爱他。
Really?
真的吗？
I'm not qualified to love him.
我没有资格爱他。
I shouldn't have agreed to your marriage.
我不应该同意你的婚姻。
Captain Liu.
刘队长。
Although you're strict,
虽然你很严格，
I think you're different from Director Jiang.
我觉得你和姜主任不一样。
I can feel
我可以感觉到
I can feel it.
我能感觉到。
The shiny thing
闪亮的东西
I know what's in your mind.
我知道你心里在想什么。
I went through that, too.
我也经历过。
I also want to talk to you.
我也想和你谈谈。
But today is not the right time.
但今天还不是时候。
Another time.
下一次。
Captain Liu.
刘队长。
Do you think
你认为
could Chen Jiaping
could Chen Jiaping
give us a surprise this time?
这次给我们带来惊喜吗？
Have you figured out how to get out?
你想好怎么出去了吗？
How did you get out?
你怎么出去的？
The power was cut.
电源被切断了。
Lead Nishimura here to grab the key.
带领西村来这里拿钥匙。
Officer Uchida.
内田警官。
Please stab me.
请刺伤我吧
You're trying to save me.
你正试图拯救我。
Although I was wounded,
虽然我受了伤，
I'm still alive.
我还活着。
You can't die.
你不能死。
You are the God.
你就是神。
I'm not going to kick your ass.
我不会踢你的屁股。
I won't die.
我不会死。
Listen to me.
听我说。
Now if you kill me,
现在如果你杀了我
you won't be able to go out.
你将无法出去。
And killing me
还杀了我
It won't do you any good.
这对你没有任何好处。
Then I can keep you,
那我就可以留住你了
what good does that do me?
这对我有什么好处呢？
I can give you money,
我可以给你钱
just like our promise.
就像我们的承诺一样。
You want to lie to me again?
你又想骗我吗？
In this case,
在这种情况下，
I won't lie to you.
我不会对你撒谎。
Or we end up
或者我们最终
and end up with each other.
并最终与彼此在一起。
I can swear that
我可以发誓
as long as we're both out,
只要我们俩都出去
I'll pay you back.
我会还给你的。
Without money,
没有钱，
It's useless to go out.
出去也没啥用。
Right?
正确的？
Where is the money?
钱在哪里？
I'm hiding somewhere
我躲在某个地方
could not be found by others.
无法被其他人找到。
Where is it?
它在哪里？
I can take you there.
我可以带你到那里。
But what if I tell you
但如果我告诉你呢
what if you kill me?
如果你杀了我怎么办？
You can't get out here either.
你也不能从这里出去。
Do you have a way?
你有办法吗？
Pushan Villa's cars
蒲山别墅的车
pass by every night.
每天晚上都会经过。
Pushanzhuang.
Pushanzhuang.
A charity organized by Mr. Du.
杜先生组织的一个慈善机构。
People died of starvation in the city.
城里的人都饿死了。
Pushan Zhuang's cars will
Pushan Zhuang's cars will
pull them out of the city
把他们拉出城
and buried them.
并埋葬了他们。
Get down and help!
赶紧下来帮忙吧！
Come over there.
过来吧。
Great Lord.
伟大的主。
Pass, please.
请通过。
Thank you, Your Majesty.
谢谢您，陛下。
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
Captain!
队长！
It was Pushanzhuang's carriage.
是朴山庄的马车。
The carriage that dragged those dead people is here again.
拖着那些死人的马车又来了。
That's right.
这是正确的。
Why would I not believe it?
我为什么不相信呢？
So many dead people?
死了这么多人？
I've checked already.
我已经查过了。
There're dead bodies.
那里有尸体。
Let them go.
让他们去吧。
Yes
是的
stop.
停止。
I can't hold it in anymore.
我再也坚持不住了
I'll go with you.
我和你一起去。
Come on.
快点。
Are you sure the box is still in the hotel?
你确定那个盒子还在酒店里吗？
Don't worry.
不用担心。
He must be there.
他一定在那儿。
I was captured by a traitor.
我被叛徒俘虏了。
The Japanese don't know about the box.
日本人不知道这个盒子。
What about
关于什么
did you find him?
你找到他了吗？
That's not necessary.
那没有必要。
Once fired,
一旦被解雇，
and disturbs the guests in the hotel,
并打扰酒店客人，
the Japanese might catch him again.
日本人可能会再次抓住他。
The loss outweighs the gain.
损失大于收益。
If that comes to the case,
如果是这样的话，
stop acting.
停止表演。
What you want
你想要什么
Is not money at all.
根本就不是钱。
Back in Maoshan Mountain,
Back in Maoshan Mountain,
you were in my class.
你在我的班级。
Are you a Communist Party member?
你是共产党员吗？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Did you recognize the wrong person?
你是不是认错人了？
You forgot my ability to remember everything.
你忘记了我记住一切的能力。
I recognized you when I first met you in the detention center.
我在看守所第一次见到你的时候就认出了你。
When I first saw you
当我第一次见到你时
what you want
你想要什么
Is another thing in the box.
盒子里还有另一件东西。
You know clearly
你清楚地知道
you know it clearly.
你知道得很清楚。
If you say that,
如果你这么说的话，
we're no longer in the same boat.
我们不再在同一条船上了。
I've never been in the same boat
我从未在同一条船上
with your Communist Party.
与你们的共产党。
Captain Liu,
刘队长，
dayan got in touch.
大雁联系上了。
Two-peach.
两桃子。
I have a good news for you
我有一个好消息告诉你
chen Jiaping should still be alive
陈家平应该还活着
really
真的
but his real identity
但他的真实身份
he's a Communist Party member.
他是一名共产党员。
Communist Party?
共产党？
Is there any evidence?
有证据吗？
It's our guy who escaped with him.
是我们的人跟他一起逃走的。
The name is Wang Dapu.
他的名字叫王大璞。
When he was lurking in Yan'an,
当他潜伏在延安时，
he stole the copper plate of the coin
他偷了硬币的铜板
chen Jiaping tried to get it back,
陈家平试图把它夺回来，
but he couldn't.
但他不能。
And Wang Dapu
还有王大璞
I met him in Maoshan Mountain before.
我以前在茅山见过他。
He is a Communist Party member.
他是一名共产党员。
That he is a Communist Party.
说他是共产党员。
Where Chen Jiaping is now?
陈家平现在在哪里？
Wang Dapu wanted to get rid of him,
王大璞想要除掉他，
but he ran away.
但他逃跑了。
No one knows now.
现在没有人知道。
What about
关于什么
are you feeling better now?
你现在好一点儿了吗？
But later,
但后来，
you have to apologize to Director Jiang with me.
你得跟我一起向江主任道歉。
He's in a good mood.
他心情很好。
Maybe he can show you a side of the net.
也许他可以向你展示网络的一面。
I won't go.
我不会去。
Listen to me.
听我说。
That's a must.
那是必须的。
Captain Liu,
刘队长，
how should I apologize to Director Jiang?
我该如何向姜主任道歉呢？
You've contributed a lot this time
这次你贡献很大
as an undercover in Yan'an for many years
在延安当卧底多年
mastermind with painstaking effort
苦心经营
to finally get this priceless
终于得到这个无价的
this priceless copper coin.
这枚无价的铜币。
The interests of the party and state come first.
党和国家的利益是第一位的。
For the sake of the overall interests of the Party and state,
为了党和国家的整体利益，
work with utter devotion
全心全意地工作
until my heart stops beating
直到我的心脏停止跳动
come.
来。
Have a seat.
请坐。
Sit down.
坐下。
Director Jiang,
Director Jiang,
I've just talked to Zuo Shuangtao.
我刚刚和左双涛谈过。
She also regrets very much
她也非常后悔
what she did.
她做了什么。
Why not let her write a self-review
为什么不让她写一篇自我检讨
to reflect on herself.
反思自己。
Director Jiang,
Director Jiang,
you can punish me as you like.
你可以随心所欲地惩罚我。
You just want me to pour a cup of wine for you.
你只是想让我给你倒一杯酒而已。
Is that OK?
这可以吗？
We can celebrate together.
我们可以一起庆祝。
Alright!
好吧！
Let's celebrate together.
让我们一起庆祝吧。
Chief, please.
酋长，请。
Come on.
快点。
Thank you, Director.
谢谢导演。
To help us
帮助我们
obtaining the copper plate of the coins.
获得硬币的铜板。
For the Imperial Concubine Qiao.
为乔贵妃。
To the
至
the first successful step of our plan.
我们计划成功的第一步。
Cheers!
干杯!
Cheers.
干杯。
The Communist Party of China
中国共产党
the Chinese Communist Party border area?
中共边境地区？
To be honest,
说实话，
after two years of observation and research,
经过两年的观察和研究，
they are thriving.
他们正在蓬勃发展。
Over time,
随着时间的推移，
a great threat to the Party and the state.
对党和国家构成重大威胁。
So it is more important
所以更重要的是
Is more important than anti-Japanese war.
比抗战更重要。
The chairman said
主席说
the Japanese are a threat to us,
日本人对我们构成威胁
but the Communists are the most dangerous.
但共产党是最危险的。
Destroying the economy of the border region.
破坏边境地区的经济。
Is the most important now.
现在才是最重要的。
Director, please be discerning.
导演请明辨是非。
But it came from one of the magpies.
但它来自一只喜鹊。
The formula for the border currency printing paper
边框货币印刷纸的配方
Is still missing.
至今仍下落不明。
That's right.
这是正确的。
I've been thinking about the same thing.
我一直在想同样的事情。
If the formula is really
如果公式真的是
where's the copper plate?
铜板在哪里？
It's gone.
它消失了。
Are you leaving?
你要走了吗？
Let me see you off.
让我为你送行。
Where is Left Shuangtao?
左双桃在哪里？
He went that way.
他就朝那条路走去。
Chase them!
追他们！
She can't run far.
她跑不了多远。
Let's look for her separately.
我们单独去找她吧。
Yes
是的
stop.
停止。
Turn around.
回转。
Give me the copper plate.
把铜板给我。
You know how important
你知道有多重要
Is to me?
是给我的吗？
You traitor.
你这个叛徒。
Come on.
快点。
How are you?
你好吗？
Are you all right?
你没事儿吧？
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
I almost fell into his hands.
我差点就落到他手里了。
After I escaped, I followed him secretly
我逃走后就偷偷跟踪他
I got it
我得到了它
so you know about my identity.
所以你知道我的身份。
Know?
知道？
Then you also know that
那么你也知道
what that means
那意味着什么
what does that mean?
这意味着什么？
I know.
我知道。
Why did you do that?
你为什么这么做？
For the belief
为了信仰
that I once lost and now I've found back.
我曾经失去过，现在又找回来了。
Jiang Zhaoguo and others are looking for me.
蒋兆国等人正在找我。
I'll distract them.
我会分散他们的注意力。
Stop joking around.
别再开玩笑了。
We should go together.
我们应该一起去。
They don't know you're here.
他们不知道你在这里。
Their target is me.
他们的目标是我。
You have a chance to escape.
你还有机会逃脱。
You know I'm right.
你知道我是对的。
That the copper plate
那个铜板
get the hands of Jiang Zhaoguo.
get the hands of Jiang Zhaoguo.
Alright?
好吧？
Take this.
拿着它。
Let's each take one.
我们每人拿一个吧。
Even if either of us gets caught,
即使我们中的任何一个被抓住
we will have access to the other party.
我们将能够接触到另一方。
Got it?
知道了？
See you at home.
在家见。
Come on.
快点。
Stop!
停止！
There are people around us.
我们身边就有这样的人。
You won't be able to get away.
你将无法逃脱。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
Captain Liu told me to
刘队长叫我
that he hid you here.
他把你藏在这里。
The headquarters.
总部。
That's right.
这是正确的。
Captain Liu ordered me to save you.
刘队长命令我去救你。
Luckily I found you before Director Jiang's men
还好我比江导的人先找到你
before Director Jiang's men got there.
江局长的人还没赶到。
Thank you
谢谢
jia Ping.
jia Ping.
Zhou Qingfang saved me.
Zhou Qingfang saved me.
I almost got caught just now.
我刚才差点就被抓住了。
Sorry
对不起
who told you about this place?
谁告诉你这个地方的？
Liu Wuchang.
Liu Wuchang.
Then
然后
you guys hide here for a while.
你们暂时躲在这里吧。
I'll meet up with Captain Liu.
我去见刘队长。
Director Jiang may even send people
江主任甚至可能会派人
to search for you everywhere.
到处寻找你。
Make sure you're safe before you leave.
离开前请确保您安全。
Alright.
好吧。
I ran into Liu Wuchang just now.
刚才碰到了刘无常。
I thought
我想
he wanted the copper plate.
他想要铜板。
But unexpectedly,
但没想到的是，
he told me a secret way to avoid the search
他告诉我一个避免搜查的秘密方法
then I'll come.
那我就来。
Captain Liu and Jiang Zhaoguo are different people.
刘队长和蒋兆国是不同的人。
Right.
正确的。
I misunderstood him before.
之前我误会他了。
But now,
但现在，
he chose the right way.
他选择了正确的方式。
I have many questions for you.
我有很多问题要问你。
Just go ahead.
前进吧。
You'll be four of clubs.
你们将成为俱乐部的四人。
When did you join the Communist Party?
你什么时候加入共产党的？
Nanjing.
南京。
Before you knew me,
在你认识我之前，
when I first met you,
当我第一次见到你时
I was confused,
我很困惑，
I didn't know what the future held in China.
我不知道中国的未来会怎样。
Or mine.
或者我的。
But the communist ideology
但共产主义思想
showed me the way.
给我指明了道路。
We would be together.
我们会在一起。
Why didn't I notice at all?
为什么我完全没有注意到？
What about the organization?
那组织呢？
Let me join the Communist Party secretly.
让我秘密加入共产党。
But I wanted to keep my original identity.
但我想保留我原来的身份。
Then
然后
you didn't show up on the day we agreed to register the marriage.
我们同意登记结婚的那天你没有出现。
Why did you lie to me?
你为什么骗我？
I'm not lying to you.
我没有骗你。
In fact, our organization has approved
事实上，我们的组织已经批准了
our marriage application.
我们的结婚申请。
But there was an assignment that day.
不过那天有任务。
And it was my first mission.
这是我的第一个任务。
And left without saying goodbye.
并没有说再见就离开了。
After that, he asked me
之后他问我
and asked me to carry out an undercover task.
并要求我执行一项卧底任务。
I knew at that moment
那一刻我就知道
I could never return to you again.
我再也无法回到你身边了。
That's why
这就是为什么
you left me in Nanjing.
你把我留在了南京。
Actually, I went back once.
其实我也回去过一次。
But we have discipline.
但我们有纪律。
That's why I couldn't meet you.
这就是为什么我没能见到你。
And then you left Nanjing.
然后你就离开了南京。
That's when
就在那时
I first met Jun Tong at that time.
我第一次见到佟俊就是那个时候。
And we have taken different paths since then.
从那时起我们就走了不同的道路。
But we reach the same goal by taking different paths.
但我们走不同的路，却达到了同一个目标。
Don't we meet again in Shanghai?
我们不会在上海再见面吗？
In Shanghai?
在上海？
That day in Shanghai...
那天在上海...
You were carrying out a CPC mission?
你是在执行中共的使命吗？
Zhao An almost found me anyway.
反正赵安差点就找到我了。
I have to come up with a reasonable reason
我必须想出一个合理的理由
to prove why I was at the train station.
为了证明我为什么在火车站
So you used me.
所以你利用了我。
You also used me.
你也利用了我。
Otherwise, how can I clear your suspicion of assassinating Shangshan Hu?
不然如何才能洗清你刺杀胡商山的嫌疑？
I did use you.
我确实利用了你。
But when I saw you,
但当我看到你的时候
to see you.
为了见你。
What about you?
你呢？
Are you happy?
你快乐吗？